# **Courtney Ring** Marketing Technologist

A hybrid professional with experience in roles that lie at the intersection of marketing and technology. Specialize in bridging the gap between the two areas by bringing digital solutions to marketing and creativity to technology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Cigna Global Content Management | January 2016-Present

Web Developer - Technology Early Career Development Program (TECDP)

- Maintain the company's global websites and various microsites
- Lead developer for Cigna's 2016 Corporate Responsibility Report a hand-coded AngularJS application
- Lead developer for the Individual & Family Plans open enrollment worked on the plan finder application, microsites, and scripts for component generation
- Participated in the development of the 2017 Medicare website and strategy sessions for the 2018 Medicare website
- Transitioned our Cigna Hong Kong partners onto Teamsite Content Manager worked on defect correction for the revamped site

#### Digital Marketing Specialist-Stretch Assignment

- Spend 1-2 days per week working with the Digital Design and Architecture Team
- Design updates and additions to the Digital Experience Standards
- Serve as the go-between for various projects involving both the Digital Marketing and Content Management teams. Projects include Medicare, Corporate Responsibility, and Offered Cigna Through Work
- Develop a widget library of Digital Experience Standards components to be used by the digital team

## Cigna OneView | June 2015 - December 2015

User Experience Design & Development Intern

- Worked with the UI Design team to make upgrades for Cigna's Customer Service **Application**
- Converted outdated data presentation into updated prototypes to evaluate ease of use
- Worked on an intern project to develop a web app for caregivers that helps them with caregiving duties - Team took first place against two other intern groups

# Cigna Social Media Marketing | June 2014 - August 2014

Marketing Intern

- Worked to develop and implement marketing strategies that created positive conversation and increased awareness of Cigna's benefits
- Developed a "Healthy Selfie" campaign and wrote copy for customer engagement
- Created new content for each social channel (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and YouTube)
- Managed social channels during New York's "Summer Streets" event to showcase Cigna's participation in the event

## **EDUCATION**

# University of Michigan, Class of 2015

- Major in Computer Science and Communication Studies, Minor in Spanish
- Graduated with a 3.3 GPA

#### Study Abroad, Madrid, Spain, Winter Semester 2014

- Studied Spanish Language and Culture at IES Abroad
- Studied Communications at the local university, Universidad de Complutense

#### CONTACT

courtneyring@outlook.com

courtney-ring.com

linkedin.com/in/courtneyring710

248.924.5377

# **AREAS OF FOCUS**



Web **Development** 



**User Experience** Design





Data & Analytics Digital Strategy

#### KEY SKILLS

HTML/CSS Google Analytics

Python **HP** Teamsite Javascript Photoshop

Git **AxureRP** 

**Bootstrap AngularJS** 

SQL BrightEdge

LinuxTerminal **SASS** 

**j**Query Chrome Devtools

For more information **CHECK OUT MY PORTFOLIO AT:** 

WWW.COURTNEY-RING.COM